SAMUEL TAN ZHI WEI

samueltan.9803@gmail.com · https://www.linkedin.com/in/tanzhiweisamuel · 83820207

Dedicated Computer Science Student with a passion for all thing tech related. Experience with Data Analytics, Software Engineering and Machine Learning. Confident in my ability to quickly pick up anything I'm passionate about, committed to continuous self-improvement and impacting team success.

Portfolio: https://react-portfolio-ghn110dho-hypotheticalwhale.vercel.app

WORKING EXPERIENCE

SATS Software Engineering Intern (Full-Stack) | TypeScript

May 2023 - Aug 2023

- Developed two minimum viable product (MVP) web applications using **Next.js** for frontend and **Prisma** for backend.
- Collaborated closely with cross-functional teams, including product managers, working in an agile methodology.
- Ensured responsive designs and optimized user experience, whilst implementing a robust backend architecture.

PSA Data Analytics Intern

May 2022 – Dec 2022

- Used Pandas | Python to analyze shipping routes and other shipping related information.
- Streamlit to Dashboard shipping information Data analytic skills to extract insights to support port planning.
- Created a script funnel for generating vessel port of rotation as well as port to port coordinates, utilizing machine learning techniques to identify complex patterns.

NIUM Product Intern May 2021 – Aug 2021

- MongoDB | NoSQL to support Product team.
- Enhanced user experience by identifying AML (anti-fraud) hits were inefficient | Collaborated with Product Analytics teams to develop and implement **MongoDB Chart** to visualize inefficiencies in real time.

1st Commando Battalion - Singapore Armed Forces | 3SG (Third Sergeant)

Jul 2018 - May 2020

• Managed team of men, overseeing discipline, training, and professional growth.

PROJECTS

GODOT | GDScript Current

- Art, Music, and Logic
- https://phatwhale.itch.io/

NFT Marketplace App + Showcase Webapp | React + React Native | JS

2022

- React Webapp, Simple proof of concept for JS, HTML, CSS
- React Native NFT Marketplace, UI for an NFT Marketplace app (Static Data)
- https://nft-showcase-react.vercel.app

Information Retrieval Dashboard + NLTK | Streamlit + Pandas | python

2023

- Google clone + Sentiment Analysis, search, re-index and scraping
- Data crawled from twitter API
- https://github.com/HypotheticalWhale/Streamlit_Information_Retrieval

EDUCATION

Nanyang Technological University Degree in Computer Science | GPA 4.22

Aug 2020 – Current

- Basketball Hall 2020-2023, Swimming IVP 2020-2023, Swimming Captain 2021-2022
- Saraca Hall Vice-President 2021-2022, Saraca Hall Welfare Director 2020-2021

Singapore Polytechnic

Apr 2015 - Mar 2018

Diploma in Aerospace Electronics | GPA 3.84

- Gold with Honors CCA, Certificate in Aviation Management, Japanese Language 1&2 Distinction
- LEAP Camp Foundation & Intermediate (Leadership camps), Water polo Captain 2016-2017

LANGUAGE AND TECHNOLOGIES

- C++, C, Java, Python, NoSQL, SQL, JavaScript, Typescript, CSS, HTML
- React, React Native, Pandas, Django, PowerBI, Next.js, Prisma, MongoDB